backyardchickencoops.com.au 2019-03-07

# Privacy Policy

**Last Updated** : 6 August 2018 / 3.48PM AEST 

This Privacy Policy ( **Privacy** **Policy** ) outlines how your information is collected, used and disclosed when you access or use Backyard Chicken Coops™ Services as defined in our Terms and Conditions ( **Terms** ).  This information is collected, used and disclosed in accordance with the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Commonwealth) ( **Privacy Act** ). This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into our Terms **.** Any capitalised terms not defined in this Policy are defined in the Terms. You agree to comply with all Terms when accessing or using our Services, including this Privacy Policy.

We collect Personal Information, as defined in the Privacy Act (including Sensitive Information as defined in the Privacy Act), when you register, use, subscribe to or take part in any of our Services.

## 2.1. Personal Information provided by you

We collect information that you knowingly and voluntarily provide to us via use of our Services as well as through any other means used to contact us (such as email, LiveChat, phone, Skype or other electronic communication technology, webforms or social media).   The kinds of Personal Information we collect include your contact and payment information such as your name, email address, organisation, address, phone number, mobile number, password, billing information. For example, we may need to collect such information to provide you with further services, register your membership to our Services or to answer or forward any requests or enquiries. We may also collect information about whether you opt-in or opt-out of our newsletters or promotional material.

## 2.2. Automatically collected Personal Information

We automatically record information from your device and its software when you access our Services, including your IP address, browser and device type, internet service provider, mobile phone carrier, platform type, the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave our Website, date and time stamp and cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or account. When accessing our Services using a mobile device, we may also receive and collect identification numbers associated with your device, mobile carrier, device type and manufacturer, and, if enabled, geographical location data (including GPS).  Please note that some of the information we collect, for example an IP address, can sometimes be used to approximate a device's location.

## 2.3. Personal Information collected via cookies

Our Services may use small pieces of data called cookies to identify a user who engages with our Website and to compile records of a user's history of engaging with our Website.  Cookies are stored by a users' browser while the user browses a website.  Cookies do not usually contain information that personally identifies a person, but each time the user visits the Website, the browser sends the cookie data back to the server to notify the system of the user's previous activity. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your browser settings.  Please note that if you disable or limit the cookies on your browser or computer, then you may obstruct the functionality of our Services, including the online shopping functionality.   We also use Google Analytics, which allows us to anonymously track the use of our Website by recording the number of users who have visited, the number of pages viewed, navigation patterns, what systems users have and the date and time of visits through cookies. This information is collected for statistical purposes only and cannot be used to identify you. Our Services also use cookies for retargeting, behaviour-based marketing and measuring advertising effectiveness. At times we may share the information gathered with our advertising partners (like Google, Facebook and Pinterest).  The information collected via these cookies are used to improve our Website, products, and to market our products to the people who want them. We think that's pretty neat, but if you disagree, you can opt out of Google remarketing here: [www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/anonymous](http://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/anonymous), Facebook remarketing here:  _[Facebook Ad Settings](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen)_ and Pinterest by turning off Personalisation in  _[your account settings.](https://www.pinterest.com/settings)_

## 3.1.  Storage of Personal Information

We take reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  The Personal Information we collect from you is transferred and stored electronically via a secured SSL connection, in secured, password-protected servers located in the United States of America and Australia.

## 3.2.  Storage of Personal Information on third party platforms

Our Services utilise and are provided using a number of different platforms, including payment platforms, which may be located in, or store data, in international locations ( **Third Party Platform** ).  These Third Party Platforms may include [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/au/home), [OpenPay](https://www.openpay.com.au/), [ZipPay](https://zip.co/) and [LiveChat](https://www.livechatinc.com/).   If you elect to pay via a Third Party Platform, the Third Party Platform may collect, transmit or store data such as your full name, address and billing address, billing information, phone number and email.   The privacy policies and terms and conditions of relevant Third Party Platforms will apply.  It is your responsibility to read, agree to and comply with such privacy policies and terms and conditions and to identify which country such Third Party Platforms are based.   You acknowledge and agree that Backyard Chicken Coops has no control over the security or privacy policy of Third Party Platforms and that Backyard Chicken Coops is not liable for any loss or damage to you in connection with any breach of this Privacy Policy or any data breach by any Third Party Platform.  To the maximum extent permitted by law, Backyard Chicken Coops shall not be liable for the act, omission, negligence or the privacy conduct of any such Third Party Platform.

## 3.3.  Who can access your Personal Information?

Your Personal Information is accessible to our employees, contractors and our third-party service providers such as our website host and technical support providers.  We may also store your Personal Information in password-protected email databases for the purpose of sending out communications and marketing emails in accordance with this Privacy Policy.   Where a Third Party Platform is used, that Third Party Platform, including its employees, may have access to your Personal Information.  Please see their privacy policies or terms and conditions for more information.   Please note that no method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure and we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your Personal Information.  It is your responsibility to ensure that you keep your Personal Information safe.  This includes keeping your software up to date to prevent security breaches.  If you are aware of any unusual activity or unauthorised access (either actual or potential) to your credit cards, etc., you must notify us immediately so that we may take the necessary steps to mitigate loss and prevent further breaches of security.   We reserve the right to maintain and store any information or data where, we reasonably believe, in our sole discretion, that such action is required to comply with any legal or regulatory obligations, to prevent criminal or other unlawful activity whether immediate or in the future, or where we have a legitimate business reason to do so, including collection of amounts owed, resolving disputes, enforcing our Terms of Use or for record keeping integrity.   We destroy or de-identify your Personal Information where it is no longer needed for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.

We collect your Personal Information as outlined in this Privacy Policy for the purposes described below:

  * for provision of the Services;
  * for administration and maintenance of your Backyard Chicken Coops products and Services;
  * for processing payments for purchases that you make from us;
  * for communication with you and to provide messaging and/or communications to you in association with the functions and features of the Services;
  * for communicating to you any announcements and updates, updated terms, conditions and policies, security alerts, technical notices, purchase confirmation, invoices, support and administrative messages;
  * for analysis, monitoring, development and improvement of our Services, including other products or services;
  * for security purposes, including to protect the Services and our property from abuse, fraud, malicious, unauthorised access or potentially illegal activities, and to protect our rights, safety and property and that of our other users;
  * for sending marketing communications to you, including notifying you of promotional or advertising offers, contests and rewards, upcoming events and other news about products and services offered by us and use of our Services; and
  * for the performance of other functions described at the time of collection or as consented to in relation to our Services.

You agree and expressly and indefinitely consent to us contacting you for any of the above purposes, including in by phone, between the hours of 8:00am - 8:00pm, 7 days a week.

Disclosure of your Personal Information will occur in accordance with the purpose for which it was collected or as outlined in this Privacy Policy.  Accordingly, your Personal Information may be disclosed to other individuals and companies as outlined below:

## 5.1.  Backyard Chicken Coops and Related Bodies Corporate

Your Personal Information may be accessed by us, including our directors, employees, officers and contractors.  You consent to us providing your Personal Information, including Sensitive Information to our Related Bodies Corporate (as defined in the _Corporations Act 2001_ (Cth)).

## 5.2.  Parties required by law

Your Personal Information may be disclosed by us to any party to whom we are required by law to provide your Personal Information and to any party to whom disclosure is permitted under the Australian Privacy Principles.

## 5.3.  Direct marketing

You agree and expressly and indefinitely consent to us using or disclosing Personal Information (other than Sensitive Information) to keep you informed about our products and services and other products and services that we consider may be of interest to you. For this purpose, disclosure may be made to our third-party service providers.  We may communicate with you via phone, email, social media, SMS, or regular mail.  If you have indicated a preference for a method of communication, we will endeavour to use that method wherever practical to do so.   We may use or disclose Sensitive Information about you for the purpose of direct marketing if you have consented to the use or disclosure of the information for that purpose.   You can opt-out of direct marketing communication activities undertaken by us at any time by clicking the unsubscribe or opt-out on email communications from us, replying 'Stop' to a promotional SMS or by contacting us by phone or email. Note if you opt-out of non-promotional messages necessary for the provision of Services to you, we may not be able to provide the Services to you. Consent to be contacted by phone can be withdrawn at any time simply by notifying a customer sales and service agent at time of call.

## 5.4. Other third parties

We may share your Personal Information with third parties if it is reasonably related to the provision of our Services.  The third parties that we may share your Personal Information with includes consultants and other service providers to us that perform services on our behalf or who offer goods and services through the Website.  Such services we procure may include identifying and disseminating advertisements, enforcement of our terms and conditions, providing fraud detection and prevention services, processing payments, delivering goods, assembling goods or providing analytics services.  We may also share your Personal Information with our business partners who offer goods or services to you jointly with us (for example, contests or promotions). We may share your Personal Information where we have reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against anyone damaging, injuring, or interfering (intentionally or unintentionally) with our rights or property, users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. We may also share your Personal Information with third parties with your consent in a separate agreement, in connection with any company transaction (such as a merger, sale of assets or shares, reorganisation, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company or third party) or in the event of bankruptcy, dissolution, divestiture or any related or similar proceedings. Note that we reserve the right to share your Personal Information with other third parties where, in our sole discretion, it is required to:

  * investigate and defend ourselves against any third party claims or allegations;
  * protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Backyard Chicken Coops, its users or the public as required or permitted by law; and
  * detect, prevent or otherwise address criminal (including fraud or stalking), security or technical issues.

## 5.5. Overseas disclosure

Please note that some of the parties listed above to whom your Personal Information may be disclosed, may be located overseas, including the Philippines, Ukraine and India. We use reasonable steps to ensure that these parties are either governed by substantially similar, accessible and enforceable laws to the Australian Privacy Principles or adhere to the Australian Privacy Principles, however to the maximum extent permitted by law, we are not liable for the privacy practices of such parties. By accessing, registering, using or subscribing to our Services, acknowledge and consent to disclosure of Personal Information to such overseas recipients. If the GDPR applies (as defined in clause 11), transfers of your Personal Information to another country or international organisation will only take place in accordance with the GDPR, where that country or organisation has provided appropriate safeguards and on the condition that you have enforceable data rights and effective legal remedies.

Our Services may, from time to time, contain links to and from websites which are owned or operated by other parties. These websites are governed by their own privacy policies and we recommend that you make your own enquiries as to their privacy policies.  We do not make any representation about and are not liable for any information on, or the privacy practices of, any third-party websites, whether or not linked from our Services.

We encourage users to ensure their Personal Information is as accurate, up to date and complete as possible in order to obtain the best value from our Service.  We may refuse to provide access if the law allows us to do so, in which case we will provide reasons for our decision as required by law. You can contact us using the details below for assistance in viewing, accessing or changing your Personal Information, or if you would like to opt-out of any marketing communications or emails.  Please note that if you change the information in your account or opt out of receiving certain communications, this will only affect future communications from us.

You may submit a written complaint about how we handle your Personal Information to our Privacy Officer via the details below. If you are not satisfied with our handling of your complaint or we have not replied to you within a reasonable period of time, then you are entitled to make a complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner or, if you are in the EU, a data protection authority or supervisory authority.

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy from time to time as we see fit.  While we endeavour to notify you as soon as reasonably possible of any changes to our Policies by email or by a notice on our Website, it is your responsibility to keep up to date with any changes or amendments by checking this page prior to using our Services. This page contains our most accurate and up to date version of our Privacy Policy.

Please address all enquiries, updates, requests and complaints to our Privacy Officer at the details below: Attn: Privacy Officer Backyard Chicken Coops Pty Ltd (ACN 138 591 625) trading as Backyard Chicken Coops Backyard Chicken Coops PO Box 2775 New Farm QLD 4005 Phone: 1300 920 906 Email: [sales@backyardchickencoops.com.au](mailto:sales@backyardchickencoops.com.au)

For the purpose of clarity, data processing of individuals in the European Union (EU) is carried on only occasionally and as such, no EU representative has been designated, however the General Data Protection Regulation ( **GDPR** ) (EU) 2016/679 may apply to you if you are resident of, reside in or are located in the EU.   If the GDPR applies, in this Privacy Policy, Personal Information shall also include the definition of 'Personal Data' under the GDPR and terms that are defined in the GDPR shall be defined in this Privacy Policy in accordance with the GDPR. If the GDPR applies, this paragraph applies in addition to the above paragraphs to the extent that we are acting as a "Data Controller" with respect to your Personal Information.

## 11.1. Consent and right to withdraw consent

By clicking accept to this Privacy Policy or otherwise notifying us of your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, you agree that you are providing express, freely given consent to us processing your Personal Information for the purposes outlined above and that we may lawfully process your Personal Information on the basis of this consent.   To the extent that our legal basis for processing your Personal Information is consent, you have a right to withdraw consent to the collection of your Personal Information at any time by sending us a written request to do so via the contact details above.

## 11.2. Legal Basis

Our legal bases for collecting and processing your Personal Information for the purposes listed above may be:

  * your express consent;
  * for our legitimate interests in providing information about the Services to you or providing the Services to you and improving and developing the Services; and/or
  * in order to perform a contract (whether verbal or written) for you in order to provide paid Services to you.

## 11.3. Your rights

We have summarised your rights under the GDPR, but please note that not all of the details of your rights have been included in these summaries.  Please ensure to read the relevant laws and guidelines for a full explanation of these rights. You may exercise these rights by contacting us to notify us of the rectification or provide information to complete your Personal Information.

  * **Right of access**

You have a right to obtain confirmation as to whether or not your Personal Information is being processed and, if so, you may request access to that Personal Information and further information including the purposes of the processing, the categories of Personal Information concerned and the recipients of the Personal Information. The first copy of such information will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.  

  * **Right of rectification**

You have the right to obtain the rectification of inaccurate Personal Information concerning you and you have the right to have incomplete Personal Information completed.

  * **Right to erasure**

You have the right to obtain the erasure of your Personal Information without undue delay if:

  * the Personal Information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed;
  * you withdraw consent to consent-based processing;
  * you object to the processing under certain rules of the GDPR; or
  * the Personal Information has been unlawfully processed.

However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure such as where processing is necessary to exercise the right of freedom of expression and information, for compliance with a legal obligation, for reasons of public interest, or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

  * **Right to restriction of processing**

You have the right to restrict the processing of your Personal Information if: 

  * you contest the accuracy of the Personal Information;
  * processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure;
  * we no longer need the Personal Information for the purposes of our processing, but you require Personal Information for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or
  * you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection.

Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your Personal Information, however we will only process it with your consent, for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person, or for reasons of important public interest.

  * **Right to data portability**

To the extent where your Personal Information has been provided based on consent, under a contract, or where processing is carried out by automated means, you have a right to receive Personal Information concerning you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and you have a right to transmit that data to a Data Controller, except where this would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

  * **Right to object**

You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your Personal Information for this purpose.
